<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Configuration on Mesen Documentation</title><link>/configuration.html</link><description>Recent content in Configuration on Mesen Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/configuration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Audio Options</title><link>/configuration/audio.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/configuration/audio.html</guid><description>General Options Audio Device: Selects which device is used for audio output (e.g computer speakers, or a headset)
Sample Rate: Selects the sample rate for the audio output &amp;ndash; typically, computers output at 44,100Hz or 48,000Hz, so they usually offer the best sound quality.
Latency: This represents the length of the buffer used in audio processing. A smaller value results in less delay between the audio and video, however, depending on the hardware used, a value that is too small may cause sound problems.</description></item><item><title>Input Options</title><link>/configuration/input.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/configuration/input.html</guid><description>General Options Console Type: Selects which console to emulate for all input ports. The NES and Famicom have different accessories and some of the identical accessories (e.g the Zapper) have different behavior on a hardware level. If you want to connect Famicom-only accessories that plug into the Famicom&amp;rsquo;s expansion port, select Famicom.
Automatically configure controllers when loading a game: When enabled, when loading any game recognized by Mesen&amp;rsquo;s internal game database, the appropriate controllers will automatically be setup.</description></item><item><title>Video Options</title><link>/configuration/video.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/configuration/video.html</guid><description>General Options Scale: The scale determines the emulator window&amp;rsquo;s size - use integer factors (e.g: 2x, 3x, 4x) for best results.
Aspect Ratio: The NES' internal aspect ratio is almost square (Default (No Stretching)), but it used to be displayed on CRT TVs that had a rectangular picture. To simulate a CRT TV, you can use the Auto option - it will switch between NTSC and PAL aspect ratios depending on the game you are playing.</description></item><item><title>Emulation Options</title><link>/configuration/emulation.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/configuration/emulation.html</guid><description>General Options Emulation Speed: This configures the regular speed to use when emulating. This should normally be set to 100%.
Fast Forward Speed: This is the alternate speed that is used when the Fast Forward button is held down.
Rewind Speed: This configures the speed at which to rewind the gameplay when the Rewind button is held down.
Run Ahead: Run ahead allows the reduction of input lag by the number of frames specified.</description></item><item><title>Preferences</title><link>/configuration/preferences.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/configuration/preferences.html</guid><description>General Options Display Language: Selects in which language the UI is shown &amp;ndash; defaults the user&amp;rsquo;s default language.
Automatically check for updates: When enabled, Mesen will check for a new version of the emulator every time the emulator is started.
Only allow one instance of Mesen at a time: When enabled, only a single copy of Mesen can be opened at the same time. This is useful when using file associations to load games by double-clicking on the rom files.</description></item></channel></rss>